# Frédéric Dubouchet

frederic.dubouchet@gmail.com | +41 (79) 104 85 76

## RESUME OBJECTIVE

Developer for 20 years in a multiples companies including some of the biggest in the industry (CERN, Google), I hope I can bring some of my knownledge in embedded and big data system to my future employer. Having contacts in the industry in both the French and the German part of Switzerland, I can be a valuable addition in any company to achieve their goal.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **HES-SO // MASTER**

MSE IN INFORMATION AND

COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES

2011 - 2013 | Lausanne, CH Thesis: (6/6) - Betatron tune measurement with the LHC damper using a GPU

#### HES-SO // HEPIA

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2002 - 2005 | Geneva, CH Thesis: (5.5/6) - 3D stereoscopy

#### **EPFL**

#### COMPUTER SCIENCE

1997 - 1999 | Lausanne, CH Unfinished - Founded of a company

#### **MATURITÉ**

#### Type S. scientifique

1997 | Geneva, CH

Grad. (74/90) - Swiss secondary school degree

### LINKS

Github://anirul

LinkedIn:// Frédéric Dubouchet

## COURSEWORK

#### **GRADUATE**

Artificial Intelligence + Practicum Cryptography Software Security

Optimizations

Fourrier and Wavelets

Web Data Mining

GPU computing

Cloud computing

#### **UNDERGRADUATE**

Digital Signal Processing Compilers + Practicum Theory of Computation Operating Systems

Databases

Virtual Marchine + Practicum Computer Graphics + Practicum

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### ORIGINAL SCORE | FOUNDER, CEO

March 2019 - Now | Lens, CH

Realization of a game to be release on Steam

- Organizing with Editors and financial sector
- Managing a team of graphists and game designers

#### **GOOGLE** | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

October 2015 - February 2019 | Zurich, CH

Working on Google Shopping from anti-spam to database

- Database writing for the Google Shopping group (C++/OpenCV)
- Reviewing process for online automatic purchase (C++/Javascript/Java)
- Version checking system from online automatic purchase (C++)

#### IDIAP RESEARCH INSTITUT | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

August 2014 - August 2015 | Martigny, CH

Developer for research projects

- Teaching computer vision to researchers (C++/OpenCL/OpenCV)
- Robotic and computer vision projects (C++/OpenCL/CUDA/OpenCV)
- ASR Automatic Speech Recognition (python)

#### **EPFL - MOKASTUDIO** | Senior Software Engineer

February 2014 - July 2014 | Lausanne, CH

CTI project for a 3D animation and inverse kinematic application

• Writing a full forward scene graph (C++)

#### **CERN** | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2006 - December 2013 | Geneva, CH

Software and drivers for controling custom harware board in a realtime environment, on LynxOS and then Linux

- Leader for the Linac4 RF control system (C++)
- LHC RF Beam control: architecture, coordination, implementation (C++)
- ADT damper: architecture, coordination, implementation (C++/OpenCL)
- LHC conditionning for the cavities, implementation (C++/Labview)

#### NAGRAVISION - KUDELSKI | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2001 - 2002 | Lausanne, CH

Content management and encryptions for digital television

• Porting the software from Win32 to Linux and TRU64 UNIX (C/C++)

#### LYSIS SA | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2000 - 2001 | Lausanne, CH

Content management and encryptions for digital television

• Multiplexer driver for digital trelevision (C)

#### **ELEAF SARL** | FOUNDER, SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2000 - 2001 | Geneva, CH

Web deveolopement mostly backend

- COM objects for Web/ASP FTP, POP3, IMAP interfaces (C++)
- Multimedia Java Applets (Java)

## RESEARCH

#### **CERN** | GRADUATE RESEARCH

July 2013 - December 2013 | Geneva, CH

Betatron tune measurement with the LHC damper using a GPU with Prof. Paul Albuquerque and Dr. Wolfgang Höfle during my master thesis. A system to make realtime fourrier transform on GPU to be able to better react to instabilities in the LHC beam using the ADT damper. It was presented at the IBIC 2013 conference in Oxford, UK.

#### **HEPIA** | Undergraduate Research

Jan 2013 - Apr 2013 | Geneva, CH

A simple study of OpenCL and comparaison with CUDA made for the Hepia. Implementation of various algorithms using OpenCL, available on **github**.

### **TEACHING**

#### **EPAC** | ÉCOLE PROFESSIONNELLE DES ARTS CONTEMPORAINS

September 2019 - July 2020 | 40% | Saxon, CH

- Game Engine technologies (C++/OpenGL/gRPC/Socket/...)
- Handling of Unreal 4 (C++/Blueprint)

#### **SAE** | CREATIVE MEDIA EDUCATION

February 2019 - Now | once per month | Geneva, CH

- Game Engine technologies (C++/Socket/...)
- Handling of Unreal 4 (C++/Blueprint)

#### **SGA** | Swiss Game Academy

July 2019 | Fribourg, CH

• Handling of Unreal 4 (Blueprint)

## SKILLS

#### LANGUAGE | NATURAL

French Mother tongue

English Fluent
German Rusted
Japanese Beginner

#### PROGRAMMING | Languages & OS

Over 100'000 lines C++ • C

Over 10'000 lines JavaScript • protobuf • Java • Python

Over 1'000 lines • LATEX • XML/XSD • Assembly • gRPC • LUA

Familiar git • make • cmake • PostgreSQL • sqlite • Blueprint

OS iOS • Windows • OSX • Linux • FreeBSD

## AWARDS AND PROJECTS

2001	Ping	32k game	C++	6 <sup>tn</sup> at Mekka and Symposium
2002	El Loco Megabus	32k game	C++	1 <sup>st</sup> at Mekka and Symposium
2005	panoptriptikum	intro 4k	8Bit-Script	2 <sup>nd</sup> at Breakpoint
2006	Biolite	96k game	C++	6 <sup>th</sup> at Breakpoint
2009	miniDHT	network	C++,protobuf	Distributed Hash Table (P2P)
2010	Biolite Reloaded	game	C++	1 <sup>st</sup> at Buenzli
2012	MOLA Parser	research	C++	Parsing of NASA Mars Orbital Laser Altimetry
2014	See Mark	game	C++	Epic Game Jam
2015	CPPS UE4	research	Blueprint	Multiscreen setup for use in an earthquake simulator
2015	Mirages	game	Blueprint	Global Game Jam
2015	Meow Zedong,	game	Blueprint	Epic Game Jam
2016	Green Revenge	game	Blueprint	Epic Game Jam
2017	Maneki Neko,	game	Blueprint	Epic Game Jam
2018	Isotops	game	C++,Blueprint	Nordic Game Jam
2018	Meow Zedong 2,	game	C++,Blueprint	Epic Game Jam
2019	Mini Epic City Builder	game	C++	Epic Game Jam